<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savitree Foundation</title>
    <link>https://example.org/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Savitree Foundation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2016 Savitree Foundation</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 13:00:25 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>https://example.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 13:00:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We would love to hear from you. Please drop us an e-mail or give us a call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Shree Ganesh&amp;rdquo;,&lt;br&gt;
A-024, Cosmopolis,&lt;br&gt;
Dumduma, Bhubaneswar,&lt;br&gt;
Odisha, India - 751019&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mail&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:savitreefoundation@gmail.com&#34;&gt;savitreefoundation@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Phone&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;tel:+919437035906&#34;&gt;+919437035906&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>https://example.org/about/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/about/donate/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Savitree Foundation is a self funded non-profit organization. Any donations towards our cause are welcome.
Here is how you can contribute by donating through third party transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;bank-account-details&#34;&gt;Bank Account details&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Account number&lt;/strong&gt;: 6762000100012513&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;IFSC Code&lt;/strong&gt;: PUNB0676200&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Bank&lt;/strong&gt;: Punjab National Bank&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Please contact the founding chairman Mr. Gopabandhu Kar for any clarification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Mission</title>
      <link>https://example.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;व-द-य-दद-त-व-नयम-व-नय-दद-त-प-त-रत-म&#34;&gt;विद्या ददाति विनयम्, विनय ददाति पात्रताम।&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;प-त-रत-व-द-धनम-प-र-त-धन-द-धर-म-तत-स-खम&#34;&gt;पात्रत्वाद्धनमाप्रोति धनाद्धर्मं ततः सुखम्।।&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To transform village Champati, P.O. Padmapur District, Cuttack of Orissa into a model establishment in a manner that all people, physically challenged and able-bodied, are gainfully employed, to bring about substantial improvements in the state of literacy, health and economic sustenance and finally to harness not just natural resources but also human resources through leadership and motivation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To promote continuous self-improvement in the quality of lives of the residents by generating leadership from within and creating opportunities for utilizing their resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up rehabilitation camps in tribal areas, drought hit areas, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aiding the mentally challenged by partnering with local organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehabilitation of children on platforms, streets and slums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting social awareness among tribal and other disadvantaged communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting promising students from economically weaker sections by means of full or partial scholarships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting organizations promoting art and culture both as a means of economic progress and wider recognition in the state/nation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To establish, maintain and run studentships, scholarships and render other kind of aid to students including supply of books, stipends and other incentives to study, without any - distinction of caste, color, race, creed or sex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To establish or grant aid to homes for the elderly and orphans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To grant relief and assistance to the victims during natural calamities such as famine, earthquake, flood, fire, pestilence, etc. and to give donations and other assistance to institutions, establishments or persons engaged in the above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To grant aid or render assistance to other public charitable trusts or institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To promote behavioral and attitudinal changes in women allowing them to be equal partners in the family and community through vocational training and capacity building activities and create an atmosphere fostering woman empowerment by establishing or supporting by monetary gifts or otherwise, centers and institutions dedicated to the cause above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To create environmental awareness amongst the rural community by conducting environmental education training programs, door-to-door meetings and awareness campaigns to encourage the use of non-conventional energy sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://example.org/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/team/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record rice grain yield due to scientific cropping</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/recordagriculture2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/recordagriculture2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Scientific cropping methods and agricultural implements provided by Savitree Foundation to certain farmers in Champati Village have resulted in highest ever per area yield of paddy in the region (decided by the State Department of Agriculture.). The associated scientists have prepared a &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/pdf/paddy2016.pdf&#34;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; for the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second batch of students selected</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/test2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/test2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second batch of students for the &lt;strong&gt;Each One Teach One&lt;/strong&gt; program have been selected!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second batch of students have been selected after the test was conducted at Savitree Foundation Office, Champati on 27 March, 2016, amongst 52 students from 11 schools around Padmapur region in Cuttack. After the IQ test, clinical psychologists personally met and evaluated each candidate before declaring 9 students who would receive the support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Arpita Jena, Vaishnavi Malla, Subhashree Behera, Jayprakash Biswal, Manisha Sahoo, Ratikant Sahoo, Bhakti Prasad Nayak, Ajay Behera, Ahetsam Masuk --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intensive Agricultural Development Programme Meeting</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/meetingagriculture2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/meetingagriculture2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Experts from different fields of Agriculture of IAS, SOA University and Coordinator CRTD, SOA University met the local farmers and explored the possibility of farm mechanization and suitability for crop diversification in the agricultural land neighboring the Savitree Foundation Training center. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/pdf/idapreport.pdf&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/pdf/idap2.pdf&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; was made for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src = &#34;/img/agriculture/idap1.jpg&#34; width = &#34;40%&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src = &#34;/img/agriculture/idap2.jpg&#34; width = &#34;40%&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src = &#34;/img/agriculture/idap3.jpg&#34; width = &#34;100%&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Camp conducted</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/health2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/health2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A health camp was conducted at Padmapur high school, Champati Village in collaboration with IMS and SUM hospital on 29 March, 2015.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A health camp was conducted on 29 March 2015 at Padmapur high school, champati in collaboration with IMS &amp;amp; SUM hospital. &lt;strong&gt;Free basic health checkup, speciality checkups for eye, ENT, dental, ECG, blood sugar and dermatology and super-speciality checkups in gastroenterology and cardiology&lt;/strong&gt; was provided alongwith free dispersal of required medicine. A total of &lt;strong&gt;612 people&lt;/strong&gt; benefited from this program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/img/health/health1.jpg&#34; width = 40%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/img/health/health2.jpg&#34; width = 40%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/img/health/health3.jpg&#34; width = 40%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/img/health/health4.jpg&#34; width = 40%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/img/health/health5.jpg&#34; width = 40%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/img/health/health6.jpg&#34; width = 40%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/img/health/health7.jpg&#34; width = 40%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First batch of students selected</title>
      <link>https://example.org/portfolio/test2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/portfolio/test2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first batch of students for the &lt;strong&gt;Each One Teach One&lt;/strong&gt; program have been selected!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year from 2015 onwards, bright students from &lt;strong&gt;economically backward&lt;/strong&gt; families will be selected on the basis of their performance in a &lt;strong&gt;unique IQ test&lt;/strong&gt; devised and performed by certified clinical psychologists. The foundation will bear the entire educational expenditure for these students, including special coaching till they find their own feet in the society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first batch of students have been selected after the test was conducted at Padmapur High School, Champati on 29 March, 2015, amongst 65 students from various schools around Padmapur region in Cuttack. After the IQ test, clinical psychologists personally met and evaluated each candidate before declaring 9 students who would receive the support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First batch of students selected</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/test2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/test2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first batch of students for the &lt;strong&gt;Each One Teach One&lt;/strong&gt; program have been selected!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first batch of students have been selected after the test was conducted at Padmapur High School, Champati on 29 March, 2015, amongst 65 students from various schools around Padmapur region in Cuttack. After the IQ test, clinical psychologists personally met and evaluated each candidate before declaring 9 students who would receive the support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Program</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The details for the &lt;strong&gt;healthcare&lt;/strong&gt; program.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthcare facilities in the state still needs a lot of improvement. Through our tie up with one of the best teaching hospitals of the state i.e. IMS &amp;amp; SUM Hospital, we have decided to provide specialized healthcare to the residents of Champati and surrounding villages. Doctors from specialized and super specialized wings like Medicine, Opthalmology, Paediatrics, Pulmonary Medicine&amp;lt; Neurology, Gastroenterology, Oncology etc shall camp at the foundation office at regular intervals and provide free check up facility and medicines to the patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We conducted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/posts/health2015/&#34;&gt;mega health camp&lt;/a&gt;, which helped us assess the medical requirements of the residents of the area. The specialist doctor visits are planned accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Each One Teach One Program</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/each-one-teach-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/each-one-teach-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The details for the &lt;strong&gt;Each-One-Teach-One&lt;/strong&gt; program.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, education in the rural areas is completely Government supported. Thus, students tend to drop out of school as soon as the extent of the support decreases. Moreover, not all schools in the rural areas are equipped with the necessary resources to provide a basic standard of education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are numerous intelligent students, who despite their intelligence lack formal education due to various personal factors. These students aren&amp;rsquo;t provided with a proper vision to employ their intelligence and education to shape a prosperous future for themselves and their family. We aim to identify such students through an innovatively devised &lt;strong&gt;IQ test&lt;/strong&gt;, adapted from the renowned Cambridge Self-Scoring IQ Test. We have created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/pdf/book.pdf&#34;&gt;booklet&lt;/a&gt; for the same (in Odia) with the hope that it will act as a guide for other similar endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year from 2015 onwards, bright students from &lt;strong&gt;economically backward&lt;/strong&gt; families are being selected on the basis of their performance in this &lt;strong&gt;unique IQ test&lt;/strong&gt; devised and performed by certified clinical psychologists. The foundation will enroll them in the best available local school and bear their entire educational expenditure, including special coaching, travel etc. till they find their own feet in the society. The only condition that the foundation imposes on the students is that they support one or more students through this program once they have established themselves, leading to the self-sustainability of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also hope to kindle similar programs in other parts of Odisha with like minded individuals/groups with the endeavor of providing a platform for such deserving students to make their way up in the society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krushi Vikas program</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/krushi-vikas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/krushi-vikas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The details for the &lt;strong&gt;Krushi-Vikas&lt;/strong&gt; program.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Agriculture is not profitable&lt;/em&gt; is a general consensus amongst most modern day farmers. We believe that such a notion exists because of the unscientific practices which they follow. In the champati area, we observed that farmers usually grow two crops a year: rice followed by sowing of green gram as the rain-fed crop without proper management practices. Majority areas were cultivated by tenant farmers while the total crop yield wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough for their livelihood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of scientists, from Sikha &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo; Anusandhan University, visited the village and opined that a shorter duration (120 days instead of 145 days) rice, followed by vegetable cultivation (winter and summer) would be highly profitable if proper scientific methods were to be followed. They agreed to provide the requisite input through continuous visits and evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an experimental basis, we motivated few farmers in the village to adopt the proposed methods and provided them better lift-irrigation facilities and agriculture implements. The paddy crop raised in this experiment yielded &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/posts/recordagriculture2016&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;highest ever output&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (58.6 Quintal/hectare) in the area. On the back of this achievement, many farmers have now come forward to join the movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>