<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savitree Foundation</title>
    <link>https://savitreefoundation.org/programs/krushi-vikas/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Savitree Foundation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2016 Savitree Foundation</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://savitreefoundation.org/programs/krushi-vikas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Record rice grain yield due to scientific cropping</title>
      <link>https://savitreefoundation.org/posts/recordagriculture2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://savitreefoundation.org/posts/recordagriculture2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Scientific cropping methods and agricultural implements provided by Savitree Foundation to certain farmers in Champati Village have resulted in highest ever per area yield of paddy in the region (decided by the State Department of Agriculture.). The associated scientists have prepared a &lt;a href=&#34;https://savitreefoundation.org/pdf/paddy2016.pdf&#34;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; for the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intensive Agricultural Development Programme Meeting</title>
      <link>https://savitreefoundation.org/posts/meetingagriculture2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://savitreefoundation.org/posts/meetingagriculture2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Experts from different fields of Agriculture of IAS, SOA University and Coordinator CRTD, SOA University met the local farmers and explored the possibility of farm mechanization and suitability for crop diversification in the agricultural land neighboring the Savitree Foundation Training center. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://savitreefoundation.org/pdf/idapreport.pdf&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://savitreefoundation.org/pdf/idap2.pdf&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; was made for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src = &#34;/img/agriculture/idap1.jpg&#34; width = &#34;40%&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src = &#34;/img/agriculture/idap2.jpg&#34; width = &#34;40%&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src = &#34;/img/agriculture/idap3.jpg&#34; width = &#34;100%&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krushi Vikas program</title>
      <link>https://savitreefoundation.org/posts/krushi-vikas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://savitreefoundation.org/posts/krushi-vikas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The details for the &lt;strong&gt;Krushi-Vikas&lt;/strong&gt; program.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Agriculture is not profitable&lt;/em&gt; is a general consensus amongst most modern day farmers. We believe that such a notion exists because of the unscientific practices which they follow. In the champati area, we observed that farmers usually grow two crops a year: rice followed by sowing of green gram as the rain-fed crop without proper management practices. Majority areas were cultivated by tenant farmers while the total crop yield wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough for their livelihood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of scientists, from Sikha &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo; Anusandhan University, visited the village and opined that a shorter duration (120 days instead of 145 days) rice, followed by vegetable cultivation (winter and summer) would be highly profitable if proper scientific methods were to be followed. They agreed to provide the requisite input through continuous visits and evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an experimental basis, we motivated few farmers in the village to adopt the proposed methods and provided them better lift-irrigation facilities and agriculture implements. The paddy crop raised in this experiment yielded &lt;a href=&#34;https://savitreefoundation.org/posts/recordagriculture2016&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;highest ever output&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (58.6 Quintal/hectare) in the area. On the back of this achievement, many farmers have now come forward to join the movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>